Hello friends, welcome to the site.
Today we are going to talk about how,
while taking a health insurance claim, we should
know for which services our card
is applicable, is it
applicable in OPD or IPD. So, I have already
told you about the OPD section. Many people are
also confused about which health card will be valid, that is, will it be valid
in OPD
or IPD. Many people are
confused whether their health card can be used
in OPD or IPD. We
can use it here in IPD. So, I have already
made a video about the OPD section. In this video,
I am going to tell you about the IPD section.
So let's start the video.
[Music]
Whenever we have any health related issue,
any problem,
any illness, then we go to the hospital
and consult a doctor. The
doctor tries to manage the initial process in the OPD itself.
What
happens in that is that they show us medicines for two or three days
on OPD basis and send them home,
but those medicines  If the patient does not get relief from this
and the problem increases, then the
doctor feels that now
this patient needs to be admitted, then it is
called IPD, that is, In-
Patient Department, so they call it admission.
What happens in admission, the patient is
admitted on a bed, after that they are given
treatment related to whatever problem they are suffering from,
they
keep them under observation for one day, two days, three days until the
patient gets well, then how is he admitted,
how is IPD done, so the
health policy under health insurance is
100% applicable in IPD, be it
individual policy or corporate policy,
I have already made a video about individual policy and corporate policy,
you can watch it in that and get your information, so
our health card will be accepted in IPD because the
health insurance policy has a
waiting period of one month,
after that one month waiting period we
can easily use it in IPD, there is no
problem in it if
we get admitted in any hospital  And if
that hospital is not in the panel then
we will not get cashless facility in it, we will have to make our
payment from there and after that we
will reverse those bills but our
card will also be credited to us at that time, so there is no
confusion in it, you can
use that card anytime in IBD for any problem,
but its use is for
those things, you can use your health card, there will be no
problem in that,
right from the surgery, the observation period of two or three
days,
all these things are included in the IPD,
IPD is included
according to the health insurance company, so whatever your
health card is, you
can use it in the IPD, you can read the terms of your policy, everything is
written in it in detail,
if your agent or your health
insurance company, your online portal
people did not tell you about this, then
you should watch this video, understand it and
share it with your friends, still you have
any confusion, then you should
comment in the comment section and
like the video, subscribe to the channel, see you
next video
For such videos, you must subscribe to our channel
so that you
can get the upcoming videos on time and
also turn on the notifications so that
you keep getting the notifications of every video uploaded on time. So, we will
meet
in the next video, till then, goodbye.